DIANA K. PEREZ LOPEZ

Pre-Doctoral Fellow, Yale Economics Department

diana.perezlopez@yale.edu https://dianakperezlopez.github.io/ Phone: (+1) 475 227 9497

Profile

I am a Pre-Doctoral Fellow at the Yale Economics Department and Economic Growth Center, working with Professor Orazio Attanasio on child development and alternative ways to interpret the magnitude of Randomized Controlled Trials' impacts. I have outstanding econometrics and coding skills. I am primarily interested in studying the causes of inequality, and how to mitigate it. In particular, my interests include child development, education, labor, gender, and development economics in general.

EDUCATION

Spring 2021	M.A. Economics, Universidad de los Andes, Colombia	
	cum laude, GPA 4.72 out of 5, ranked 2 out of 38	
	Thesis: "'Am I not good at it or am I not good at all?' STEM gender gaps in	
	higher education." (Grade: 5 out of 5, coded as Approved for COVID-19)	
Spring 2019	B.A. Economics, Universidad de los Andes, Colombia	
	Minor in Management, Universidad de los Andes, Colombia	

AWARDS

2021	Placed in the top 3% of the previous 5 years of graduates in the M.A. in economics,
	Universidad de los Andes, Colombia (cum laude)
2018	Placed in the top 1% in the Colombian higher education examinations (Saber Pro)
2014	Placed in the top 2% in the Colombian high school education examinations (Saber
	11)

Related Advanced Coursework

Yale University: Real Analysis (A); Universidad de los Andes, Colombia: Advanced Econometrics (5 out of 5) \cdot Econometrics and Machine Learning (5 out of 5) \cdot Long-Run Advanced Macroeconomics (4.6 out of 5) \cdot Advanced Microeconomics Game Theory (4.5 out of 5) \cdot

RESEARCH EXPERIENCE

Department of Economics and Economic Growth Center, Yale University

Pre-Doctoral/Postgraduate Fellow

Aug. 2021 - Present Principal investigator: Orazio Attanasio

Research Assistant

Feb. 2021 - Jul. 2021 Principal investigator: Orazio Attanasio

Department of Economics and CEDE, Universidad de los Andes, Colombia

Research Assistant

May 2019 - Mar. 2021	Principal investigator:	Raquel Bernal
Oct. 2018 - Jun. 2019	Principal investigator:	Fabio Sanchez
Jan. 2018 - Dec. 2020	Principal investigator:	Diego Amador

Department of Economics, Princeton University

Research Assistant

Aug. 2020 - Nov. 2020 Principal investigator: Micaela Sviatschi

Work in Progress

"Measuring Impacts in Early Child Development Interventions." With *Orazio Attanasio*, *Sarah Cattan*, *Sharon Wolf*, *Matias Placencio-Castro*, and *Marta Rubio-Codina*.

"Estimating the Production Function of Human Capital in India." With *Orazio Attanasio*, *Costas Meghir*, *Pamela Jervis*, and Alessandro Toppeta.

"The Role of Maternal and Paternal Inputs on Child Development: Evidence from a Randomized Controlled Trial in Rwanda." With *Orazio Attanasio*, *Theresa Betancourt*, *Sarah K. G. Jensen*, and *Matias Placencio-Castro*.

Teaching Experience

Universidad de los Andes, Colombia

Graduate Teaching Assistant

Spring 2019 - Spring 2021 Advanced Econometrics (masters); Prof. Raquel Bernal and

Prof. Manuel Fernandez

Fall 2019 - Fall 2020 Behavioral Economics (undergraduate); Prof. Andres Moya

Spring 2019 - Summer 2019 Forecasting (masters); Prof. Daniel Wills

Summer 2019 Advanced Impact Evaluation on Complex Models (masters);

Prof. Sergio Urzua

Undergraduate Teaching Assistant

Fall 2017 Econometrics (undergraduate)

Spring 2017 - Fall 2017 Integral Calculus and Probability (undergraduate)
Spring 2017 Probability and Statistics 1 (undergraduate)

SUMMER SCHOOLS AND COMMUNITY WORK

Nov. 2019	RIDGE Summer School in Economics
Sep. 2019	Community work: Translation of "CORE: The Economy" to Spanish
Fall 2018	Community work, "Programa Progresa Fenicia": School tutoring for low-
	income school-aged children

SKILLS

Stata and LATEX	Advanced	R and Matlab	Intermediate
-----------------	----------	--------------	--------------

LANGUAGES

English	T1 /	C • 1	TAT . •
Hingligh	Fluent	Spanish	Native
וומווצווניו	L. LOCHO	ораны	T V C U I V C

[&]quot;'Am I not good at it or am I not good at all?' STEM gender gaps in higher education."

[&]quot;GRE waving and diversity on graduate school programs"

[&]quot;Remedial courses to complement scholarship programs for low-income students"

[&]quot;Price regulation of contraceptives, teenage pregnancy, and abortion"